[WOMAN 1]: Yeah, I think he worked at, uh...
[MURDOCK]: Pimlico he worked at?
[BARNHART]: Well, I don't know about other ones, but he was here at the Fairtime and down in Charlestown.
[WOMAN 1]: Yeah.
[WOMAN 1]: Yeah, that's what he, uh...
[WOMAN 1]: But I, he had something, because he had the nurse 24 hours a day.
[WOMAN 2]: Who was that?
[WOMAN 1]: Rube Marquard.
[WOMAN 1]: But now both his school brothers are.
[WOMAN 1]: college there, balls of fire.
[WOMAN 1]: I don't know, I mean, I never know how old anybody is.
[WOMAN 1]: Joey Sewell was just hither and thither and yon.
[WOMAN 1]: He lives down in Alabama and he was up in Ohio the other weekend.
[WOMAN 1]: Because we saw him down in Alabama when our son was stationed at Venice.
[WOMAN 1]: We went down that way to see him after he got back from Germany.
[MURDOCK]: What I'd like to do is to just
[MURDOCK]: ask you about where you grew up and what your family did and how you got started in the baseball.
[MURDOCK]: Are you from Hagerstown?
[BARNHART]: No, I was up here in Pennsylvania, not very far.
[BARNHART]: I grew up on a farm.
[BARNHART]: I guess I got some of my baseball from my father.
[BARNHART]: He used to play ball.
[BARNHART]: He had a little league ball around.
[BARNHART]: He taught me a lot of baseball.
[BARNHART]: I can remember him playing ball with me when I wore dresses then.
[BARNHART]: Of course, you wore dresses then until you were old enough to go to school.
[MURDOCK]: This birth date, right?
[MURDOCK]: December 29, 1895?
[BARNHART]: That's right.
[MURDOCK]: You're 85 now?
[MURDOCK]: 84?
[WOMAN]: He's not very good at math.
[MURDOCK]: Did you learn, did you do a lot of throwing on the farm there?
[MURDOCK]: Did you have enough people to play games?
[BARNHART]: I had a little team there in the little valley.
[BARNHART]: I had a little team there.
[BARNHART]: I played on that until I started going to school.
[BARNHART]: I went to Shippensburg over there.
[BARNHART]: Graduated there in 16.
[MURDOCK]: Did they have a team?
[BARNHART]: They had a team, yeah.
[MURDOCK]: Somebody scout you at Shippensburg, or how did you break into pro ball?
[BARNHART]: Well, yeah, the Blue Ridge League had started that.
[BARNHART]: I used to go to see them play every chance I got.
[BARNHART]: In the summertime, I got on one of the teams.
[MURDOCK]: Which team do you remember?
[BARNHART]: Frederick?
[MURDOCK]: That'd be in 1960 or 17?
[BARNHART]: That was in 15.
[BARNHART]: I played with them.
[BARNHART]: It was 1916, 1917, the league closed.
[MURDOCK]: Because of the war, huh?
[BARNHART]: Yeah, I went up to Williamsport and got on a team up there.
[BARNHART]: It was a Lycoming motor team.
[BARNHART]: They played all the teams.
[BARNHART]: They called the name of Hinchman, Bill Hinchman.
[BARNHART]: He was managing that.
[BARNHART]: I played under
[BARNHART]: Well, I forget his name now, but he was with the Boston and Brooklyn Club.
[BARNHART]: He wanted me to sign up with the Brooklyn Club for a tryout.
[BARNHART]: So, Hinchman heard of this, and he came around and signed me up before the fellow did.
[MURDOCK]: He was with Pittsburgh?
[BARNHART]: Yeah.
[MURDOCK]: He was scouting for Pittsburgh?
[BARNHART]: Yeah, he was scouting for Pittsburgh.
[MURDOCK]: What'd he sign you up for?
[BARNHART]: Me, what, the salary?
[MURDOCK]: Yeah.
[BARNHART]: I think it was $350.
[MURDOCK]: That's pretty big money for you, wasn't it?
[BARNHART]: Big money at that time, yeah.
[MURDOCK]: What'd your father think of this?
[MURDOCK]: Was he quite pleased you would be playing well?
[BARNHART]: He was pleased.
[BARNHART]: He always followed it.
[BARNHART]: I had to pitch for the paper sometimes.
[BARNHART]: Followed it all the time.
[MURDOCK]: Do you have any boyhood heroes from Pittsburgh?
[BARNHART]: Like Wagner?
[BARNHART]: No, I knew Wagner.
[BARNHART]: He was a coach on a team one year when I was up there in 1920.
[MURDOCK]: So where did you play in 1918?
[MURDOCK]: In Lycoming then?
[BARNHART]: Lycoming.
[MURDOCK]: And Pittsburgh signed you that?
[MURDOCK]: after that season?
[BARNHART]: Yeah, they shined me and sent me down to Birmingham.
[MURDOCK]: How'd you like it down south?
[BARNHART]: Well, life's alright.
[BARNHART]: It was an awful hike.
[MURDOCK]: Take any of those night train rides in the summer?
[MURDOCK]: Must have been pretty warm, huh?
[BARNHART]: Yeah.
[MURDOCK]: Who was the manager of Birmingham?
[BARNHART]: I just think of it now and then.
[MURDOCK]: Were you playing outfield all these years?
[BARNHART]: No, I played at the third base.
[BARNHART]: Or infield, I played infield.
[MURDOCK]: How'd you happen to go to the outfield?
[BARNHART]: Well, I got to, when I went to Pittsburgh, I played third base for a couple years.
[BARNHART]: So, Pie Traynor, he was a pretty good infielder.
[BARNHART]: So, he switched me to the outfield, and I played the outfield.
[MURDOCK]: Did you spend all of 1920 with Pittsburgh?
[MURDOCK]: It says you played in 12 games that year.
[BARNHART]: No, that's a year.
[BARNHART]: He sent me out. When I came back and played 12 games at the end of the season.
XXX
[MURDOCK]: You hit .326 so you must have made a good debut there.
[BARNHART]: I was in the '27 series, the '25 series.
XXX
[MURDOCK]: What was it like to go up to Pittsburgh there, as a, for the first time, be with some of these people?
[BARNHART]: Well, I worked out with them in spring training, all of them, see.
[BARNHART]: They just sent me down there just before the season opened.
[MURDOCK]: Did you feel pretty confident you were going to be able to stick up there?
[BARNHART]: Well, yes.
[BARNHART]: I always had enough confidence.
[MURDOCK]: How'd you do at Birmingham?
[MURDOCK]: Must have had a pretty good year there, huh?
[BARNHART]: Yeah, I had a good year there.
[MURDOCK]: Now, who was manager at Pittsburgh when you came up there in 20?
[BARNHART]: Gibson.
[MURDOCK]: George Gibson.
[MURDOCK]: Is he still active playing, or is he still catching then?
[BARNHART]: Oh, he was catching then.
[MURDOCK]: Remember some of the other players on the team when you first came up?
[BARNHART]: You mean the Birmingham?
[MURDOCK]: No, the Pittsburgh team.
[MURDOCK]: Max Carey probably.
[BARNHART]: Oh, Max Carey was there.
[BARNHART]: Traynor.
[BARNHART]: Rawlings.
[BARNHART]: Big Ben, I think, was there.
[BARNHART]: Schmidt, catcher.
[MURDOCK]: That Earl Smith?
[BARNHART]: Yeah.
[BARNHART]: Babe Adams was one of the pitchers.
[MURDOCK]: Was Vic Aldridge with him?
[MURDOCK]: Did they give you any kind of a salary boost for 1921?
[BARNHART]: Yeah, I got a boost.
[BARNHART]: I don't remember what it was or anything.
[MURDOCK]: Did you play third base in 21?
[MURDOCK]: That was before Traynor came up, I guess.
[MURDOCK]: Who were some of the pitchers that gave you some trouble or that didn't?
[MURDOCK]: Remember Early Wynn?
[BARNHART]: How about, well... Well, Vance, he's a fastball pitcher.
[BARNHART]: Burleigh Grimes, he's a spit-baller, I believe that is.
[BARNHART]: Quite a number of them, again, just thinking of names.
[WOMAN 1]: Were you married at this time?
[WOMAN 2]: Oh, yes.
[WOMAN 1]: Did you travel with him?
[WOMAN 2]: No.
[WOMAN 2]: We weren't allowed to travel.
[BARNHART]: Oh, you made several trips.
[WOMAN 2]: Yeah, but we wasn't allowed to go to California or anything.
[WOMAN 1]: So, did you live in Pittsburgh?
[WOMAN 2]: No, no, I lived here in Pittsburgh.
[WOMAN 1]: Oh, that made it nice, though, that you had your...
[WOMAN 2]: I went to St. Louis one time, and they played there, and I was there.
[WOMAN 2]: Morris and he forgot that he was there.
[BARNHART]: John Morris.
[MURDOCK]: Eddie Moore.
[MURDOCK]: I've interviewed Eddie Moore.
[MURDOCK]: He died a couple years ago.
[MURDOCK]: He was over in Ironton, Ohio, where he was living then.
[MURDOCK]: And Carmen Hill, I've talked to him.
[MURDOCK]: Hill and Meadows were the two that wore the glasses, huh?
[MURDOCK]: What was this time you hit a home run off of?
[MURDOCK]: Who was it you mentioned earlier?
[BARNHART]: Markford?
[MURDOCK]: Yeah, Markford.
[MURDOCK]: Tell us about that.
[BARNHART]: Well, he was a left-hand pitcher.
[BARNHART]: I forget what inning it was.
[BARNHART]: 8th or 9th.
[BARNHART]: I guess it was the 9th inning.
[BARNHART]: I just hit the home run and won the game.
[WOMAN 1]: And what did you do in your off-season?
[WOMAN 1]: Did you hunt or fish?
[BARNHART]: Hunt.
[BARNHART]: Hunt fish.
[WOMAN 1]: That's what most of the fellas we talk to seem to do in their off-season.
[WOMAN 1]: Hunt and fish.
[WOMAN 2]: Well, now, yeah, but a lot of them have businesses now.
[WOMAN 2]: Oh, now, yeah, but I mean in those older ones.
[WOMAN 2]: He had to spend a year, was it a year, a year and a half, down at the pharmacy to fill a doctorate.
[WOMAN 2]: And we just had one more year to go.
[WOMAN 2]: And we tried encouraging him to go back and finish, but he couldn't go back.
[WOMAN 1]: But there have been quite a few of the older players that we talked to.
[WOMAN 1]: What did you do?
[WOMAN 1]: Well, I fished and golfed.
[WOMAN 1]: or I fished and hunted.
[WOMAN 1]: Hunting, uh, Ed Rouse.
[WOMAN 1]: And Marquardt, of course, said he was on the vaudeville stage, so, on the off-season.
[WOMAN 1]: And he went to the vaudeville circuit, I guess.
[WOMAN 1]: That's what he said.
[WOMAN 2]: And I hear from Johnny Morrison's wife.
[WOMAN 2]: She likes to go home with him.
[WOMAN 2]: He died.
[WOMAN 2]: He had diabetes, I think.
[MURDOCK]: I didn't know that.
[MURDOCK]: I hadn't really died, I didn't know.
[MURDOCK]: But tell me about the 1927 season and Kai Kai Cuyler.
[MURDOCK]: What happened there?
[MURDOCK]: Can't we talk?
[WOMAN 1]: Bang, bang, bang.
[WOMAN 1]: That's the way it went.
[BARNHART]: Didn't amount to much.
[BARNHART]: Of course, the Yankees, they were way ahead, you know.
[BARNHART]: We had to play up to the last game to win the series.
[BARNHART]: The pennant, even.
[BARNHART]: And of course, the Yankees, they just beat us four straight.
[MURDOCK]: That wild pitch.
[MURDOCK]: It ended it all.
[MURDOCK]: Bill, did you say much after that?
[MURDOCK]: What I was referring to was when Donnie Bush benched Cuyler about midway through the season and put you in place.
[MURDOCK]: And Cuyler was, wasn't he having a pretty good year or so?
[MURDOCK]: And never played him again?
[MURDOCK]: Was that what happened?
[BARNHART]: I don't know what it was.
[BARNHART]: They didn't get along too good together.
[BARNHART]: I guess for the reason.
[MURDOCK]: But here's a star hitter and he didn't play him at all or in the World Series.
[MURDOCK]: I asked Glenn Wright about that and he said, well, he didn't know either.
[MURDOCK]: There was some feeling.
[MURDOCK]: But he said he put Clyde Barnhart in there instead and that was a pretty good replacement.
[MURDOCK]: So they didn't really miss him.
[MURDOCK]: Because you finished up hitting .319 that year, 27.
[WOMAN 1]: He a great year then, did he?
[WOMAN 1]: with high batting averages.
[WOMAN 1]: He did.
[MURDOCK]: Do you have any favorite pitches you like to hit, or did you hit pretty much anything they threw up there?
[BARNHART]: Yeah, I never had much trouble hitting.
[MURDOCK]: In 1926, you only played 76 games, and your average went down.
[MURDOCK]: Were you injured that year?
[BARNHART]: Yeah, I was sick part of the time.
[MURDOCK]: What manager did you like best?
[MURDOCK]: Anybody stand out?
[BARNHART]: I guess Bush was... McKechnie was a good manager.
[MURDOCK]: Charlie Grimm, a pretty lively person?
[BARNHART]: Yeah.
[MURDOCK]: Keeping everybody loose?
[MURDOCK]: Got any stories about him you can remember, Charlie?
[BARNHART]: Oh, we had a little, kind of an orchestra in Morris, and Grimm and I, a banjo, and mandolin.
[MURDOCK]: Which did you play?
[BARNHART]: Mandolin.
[MURDOCK]: When would you perform this orchestra?
[MURDOCK]: Sure, in the clubhouse there you mean?
[BARNHART]: Well, in spring training we played out in California in the theater there in the evenings sometimes.
[BARNHART]: We had a little theater there.
[BARNHART]: And we practiced, we practiced on the road, on the rooms, or in our rooms.
[BARNHART]: in the clubhouse sometimes.
[MURDOCK]: What kind of a chap was Max Carey?
[BARNHART]: He was pretty good looking.
[MURDOCK]: Was he a leader on the field, was he?
[BARNHART]: Well, he was a base stealer, you know.
[BARNHART]: He tried to teach the fellas to run the bases.
[MURDOCK]: How'd you get along with Barney Dreyfuss?
[BARNHART]: Oh, Barney Dreyfuss was all right.
[MURDOCK]: Eddie Moore said he had all kinds of problems with him.
[MURDOCK]: I just wondered if maybe it was Dreyfuss or if it was Moore.
[WOMAN 2]: It wasn't Dreyfuss because when... where were they overseas someplace?
[WOMAN 2]: Stony Cove, under the sun.
[MURDOCK]: I guess his Eddie Moore was a little hot-headed, maybe, and that's some of the friction, because he did sell him off to Boston after the
[MURDOCK]: 25 season, I guess.
[MURDOCK]: He had a good season there.
[MURDOCK]: I think there's somebody else coming up, too.
[MURDOCK]: George Grantham on the team when you were there?
[BARNHART]: Yeah.
[BARNHART]: Harris.
[BARNHART]: We got Harris from Washington.
[MURDOCK]: He was the one that was gassed in the war, is that right?
[BARNHART]: Yeah.
[MURDOCK]: Was Earl Smith a pretty lively chap.
[BARNHART]: Yeah, pretty lively.
[BARNHART]: He used to get a lot of arguments.
[BARNHART]: Other teams, most of them managers, you'd either like McGraw or someone like that.
[BARNHART]: Puggins.
[MURDOCK]: How'd you like the umpires?
[BARNHART]: Well, they was all right.
[MURDOCK]: You ever get thrown out of a game?
[MURDOCK]: What happened there?
XXX
[BARNHART]: He just called me out on a bad ball and I tossed my bat up in the air.
[MURDOCK]: That's automatic, huh?
[MURDOCK]: You think the umpires do a pretty good job in your experience?
[BARNHART]: Well, lately, I don't know.
[BARNHART]: They got so much trouble of late.
[MURDOCK]: When you were playing?
[BARNHART]: Oh, well, they did all right.
[BARNHART]: They never had the arguments they do now.
[WOMAN 1]: Well, I know, but look what you've got playing ball now, with all these little temperamental people.
[MURDOCK]: Did you play center field most of the time?
[BARNHART]: No, mostly left.
[BARNHART]: Right field, once in a while.
[BARNHART]: Never played center much.
[MURDOCK]: You have a pretty good arm, I imagine, didn't you?
[BARNHART]: Yeah.
[MURDOCK]: Did you get many assists from the outfield?
[BARNHART]: A few.
[MURDOCK]: That's quite an achievement.
[MURDOCK]: Did you watch the All-Star game the other night?
[MURDOCK]: Dave Parker made those two assists.
[MURDOCK]: Right over the hill.
[MURDOCK]: Did you do a lot of bunting?
[BARNHART]: I bunted.
[BARNHART]: Not too awful much.
[BARNHART]: I never had any trouble learning to bunt.
[BARNHART]: I learned to bunt while I was going to school.
[MURDOCK]: Did anybody teach you or just teach yourself?
[BARNHART]: Yeah.
[BARNHART]: Coach at the college taught me.
[MURDOCK]: When you came up to the big league or even with
[MURDOCK]: down with Frederick there, did you get much help from some of the older players?
[BARNHART]: Well, not too much.
[MURDOCK]: They kind of, they figure you're trying to take a job away from them and they don't help you much, huh?
[BARNHART]: Yeah.
[BARNHART]: They was players, you know, that had been let go from other places, other teams.
[BARNHART]: First of all, the balls that you're playing with now are rubber balls.
[BARNHART]: What we had to play with.
[MURDOCK]: You mean they're much more lively, huh?
[BARNHART]: Yeah.
[MURDOCK]: Weren't they pretty lively in your time, though?
[MURDOCK]: Ruth hit all those home runs?
[BARNHART]: Well, Ruth's about the only one.
[BARNHART]: Well, it was like hitting a rock.
[BARNHART]: Ball then.
[BARNHART]: They never played much for a big inning like they do now.
[BARNHART]: They always bunted mostly and played for the one run.
[MURDOCK]: They don't know how to bunt today, really.
[MURDOCK]: I think when they're supposed to bunt, it seems to me like they deliberately miss it so they can hit away.
[BARNHART]: Well, so many of them bunt, they hold it back with both hands in the end.
[BARNHART]: I was taught to bunt, and I always slipped this hand out.
[BARNHART]: and bat and bat.
[BARNHART]: Together, they just bat and hit the ball up in the air and every place else.
[BARNHART]: I used to hit a lot of long fly balls.
[BARNHART]: that would be home runs now.
[BARNHART]: I scored three men from second base on sacrifice flies.
[BARNHART]: Carey twice and Cuyler once.
[MURDOCK]: Is that right?
[MURDOCK]: Must be some kind of a record.
[MURDOCK]: Was it your deep center field that hit the ball?
[BARNHART]: Yeah, mostly center.
[MURDOCK]: Of course, you had a big ballpark to bat in too, didn't you?
[MURDOCK]: The deepest center field there is.
[MURDOCK]: Did you like to play there?
[MURDOCK]: Was it a good fielder's park?
[MURDOCK]: It wasn't very good for hitters.
[MURDOCK]: Where did the team stay?
[MURDOCK]: When you're in Pittsburgh, did you have a rooming house or did you stay in a hotel?
[BARNHART]: You had to furnish your own room.
[MURDOCK]: You could stay with him then when he was in Pittsburgh?
[WOMAN 2]: Oh yeah, I used to take a couple of kids along.
[WOMAN 2]: We stayed in the boarding house one time, and then we had a residence.
[MURDOCK]: It's kind of hard when school's still in to take the kids along.
[WOMAN 2]: Well, I never stayed that long.
[WOMAN 2]: I only stayed when they were home.
[WOMAN 2]: In Pittsburgh, I didn't stay long.
[WOMAN 2]: Like, when they were home, I'd just drive up, and then they went on a trip, and then I'd come home.
[WOMAN 1]: And took the children with you?
[WOMAN 2]: No, I didn't ever took them all.
[WOMAN 1]: Oh.
[WOMAN 2]: I took two.
[WOMAN 2]: I took the boys, and I never allowed them out.
[WOMAN 2]: I guess when one boy was out, the others weren't.
[WOMAN 1]: How many children do you have?
[WOMAN 2]: Five.
[WOMAN 1]: Do they live around here?
[WOMAN 2]: No, one girl lives in Miami.
[WOMAN 2]: I mean, in Florida.
[WOMAN 2]: She lives in Hialeah Garden.
[WOMAN 2]: The rest of them are all around, depending on, you know, anything.
[MURDOCK]: Have you ever had any contract disputes?
[BARNHART]: No.
[MURDOCK]: Were they pretty generous, do you think?
[BARNHART]: Yeah, they were pretty generous.
[BARNHART]: I got on average about everybody.
[MURDOCK]: Did you feel spring training was necessary?
[MURDOCK]: Eddie Rouse used to hold out, so he wouldn't go to spring training.
[MURDOCK]: And you'd come and start hitting as well as ever.
[MURDOCK]: Maybe that's because you were so good.
[MURDOCK]: But do you think it really helped you get into shape?
[BARNHART]: Oh, yes.
[BARNHART]: The last time spring training.
[BARNHART]: Of course some of these stars, like Roush.
[BARNHART]: Didn't need too much to get into shape.
[MURDOCK]: You probably kept in pretty good shape in the off season with hunting and so on.
[BARNHART]: Yeah, I never took on much weight.
[BARNHART]: Wasn't hard to get down.
[MURDOCK]: Were you eager to get going next spring?
[MURDOCK]: Did you really look forward to it?
[MURDOCK]: Did any big thrills stand out in your mind as you look back on your baseball career?
[MURDOCK]: Anything particularly outstanding that you had happen to you or that you did?
[MURDOCK]: Maybe those sacrifice flies, they were something.
[BARNHART]: I remember when Pershing was out there at Pittsburgh one time.
[BARNHART]: I had to play a right fielder.
[BARNHART]: It was in the ninth inning.
[BARNHART]: The ball hit it out to me, and I went over towards the line and jumped and caught it with one hand.
[BARNHART]: That was the last out, and then it was over.
[WOMAN 2]: General Pershing were you talking about?
[BARNHART]: Yeah.
[BARNHART]: And they had a piece of the paper about it.
[BARNHART]: Pershing remarked about the catch down there.
[BARNHART]: In the 25 Series, I
[BARNHART]: I won the game that Washington had us beat, in the sixth game.
[BARNHART]: They'd won that the Series would have been over.
[MURDOCK]: I forgot about that.
[BARNHART]: Kovalewski, he was a spitball pitcher.
[BARNHART]: He had a spitball pitcher here in the Blue Ridge League, and I always liked him.
[BARNHART]: I remember hitting the lid off of him.
[BARNHART]: He won my sixth game and brought the series back to Pittsburgh.
[BARNHART]: And that's the end of it.
[BARNHART]: We won it the next day.
[BARNHART]: Seventh game.
[MURDOCK]: Did Johnson pitch that game?
[BARNHART]: Yeah.
[MURDOCK]: Did you hit any of those ground balls that Roger Peckinpah fumbled?
[BARNHART]: No, I didn't hit any.
[MURDOCK]: He set a series record of eight errors, you know.
[BARNHART]: Yeah.
[MURDOCK]: He'd been voted the most valuable player in the league just before the World Series.
[MURDOCK]: And after he made eight errors, a number of people said they should hold the voting after the series.
[MURDOCK]: But he was quite, I spent an evening with him one day and talked to him about those errors.
[MURDOCK]: And he said that the Pittsburgh scorers were prejudiced against him because they wanted, see, Honus Wagner had the record of six errors by a shortstop in a World Series game.
[MURDOCK]: And the Pittsburgh Scores wanted Wagner to break that, wanted that record broken so it wouldn't be with Wagner.
[MURDOCK]: So they gave Peckinpah some errors which he felt he didn't deserve.
[MURDOCK]: I guess some of the days the field was a little muddy and the ball was a little heavy or something.
[MURDOCK]: It was kind of hard fielding and his throws were just a little bit low or something that normally wouldn't have been.
[MURDOCK]: And Max Carey wrote that one of those errors was
[MURDOCK]: If he hit the ball, it should have been a base hit.
[MURDOCK]: He felt he'd been robbed of the base hit by the scorer.
[MURDOCK]: I just wonder if you did any of those, which Peckinpahl might have done.
[BARNHART]: No, I don't think so.
[MURDOCK]: How was Walter Johnson to hit against?
[BARNHART]: Well, he was pretty speedy.
[BARNHART]: I was considered a curveball hitter.
[BARNHART]: He didn't throw me any curveballs.
[BARNHART]: He was all fastball.
[BARNHART]: He hit me right in the chest.
[MURDOCK]: He hit you?
[MURDOCK]: For you, did you crowd the plate much?
[MURDOCK]: Or did it just get away from him?
[BARNHART]: Just naturally, just trying to pitch inside.
[MURDOCK]: Did you get any hits off him, do you remember?
[BARNHART]: I did.
[MURDOCK]: That's something.
[MURDOCK]: Yeah, we talked to Kovalewski, too.
[MURDOCK]: He was one of those we talked to.
[BARNHART]: You talked to him?
[MURDOCK]: Yes, Stan Kovalewski.
[MURDOCK]: He's out in Indiana.
[WOMAN 1]: I always want to say Big Bend, but that isn't it.
[MURDOCK]: South Bend.
[WOMAN 1]: South Bend, where Notre Dame is.
[MURDOCK]: Yeah.
[MURDOCK]: Loves to fish.
[MURDOCK]: Still goes fishing.
[WOMAN 1]: Yeah, every day.
[WOMAN 1]: He couldn't let him interfere.
[WOMAN 1]: He could be there at a certain time, but he wouldn't interfere with his fishing.
[MURDOCK]: Did you play any ball after you left the Pirates?
[BARNHART]: Yeah, I played in the American Association.
[MURDOCK]: Where did you play with them?
[BARNHART]: Indianapolis.
[MURDOCK]: Was Eddie Sicking with Indianapolis?
[BARNHART]: Eddie who?
[MURDOCK]: Sicking.
[MURDOCK]: Second baseman.
[MURDOCK]: He may have come a little later.
[BARNHART]: Is that what they call him?
[BARNHART]: Is that his real name?
[MURDOCK]: Yeah.
[MURDOCK]: S-I-C-K-I-N-G.
[MURDOCK]: He played with Indianapolis at some time, but I don't know if those were the years or not.
[MURDOCK]: He may have been.
[BARNHART]: I can't really say.
[WOMAN 2]: We went to Indianapolis right after that Pittsburgh.
[BARNHART]: Yeah.
[BARNHART]: I went to Pittsburgh, too, I think.
[MURDOCK]: Was that a pretty big disappointment to you when you left the Pirates?
[BARNHART]: Oh, no.
[BARNHART]: I figured I might get back again when I'm out of here.
[WOMAN 2]: You went to Jersey City.
[MURDOCK]: Yeah, then I went to... How long were you in Indianapolis?
[MURDOCK]: A year or two?
[BARNHART]: Two years, I believe.
[MURDOCK]: And then you went to Jersey City?
[MURDOCK]: Well, did you play any night baseball?
[BARNHART]: A couple nights.
[BARNHART]: I didn't.
[MURDOCK]: Where was it?
[MURDOCK]: In Indianapolis?
[BARNHART]: Indianapolis, I believe.
[MURDOCK]: Lights weren't too bright, huh?
[BARNHART]: No, they weren't too good.
[BARNHART]: That's another thing.
[BARNHART]: When I played, I always had my thumbs always bruised up from when I was hitting.
[BARNHART]: That would sting your hands.
[BARNHART]: They wouldn't let you wear gloves then, but everybody can wear gloves now.
[BARNHART]: That would help a batter a whole lot.
[BARNHART]: I used to have a sponge that I'd tape on my bat to get it un-parsed.
[MURDOCK]: How big was your glove compared to those today?
[BARNHART]: Oh, it was just small.
[MURDOCK]: Did you have much padding in it?
[BARNHART]: No, nothing in it.
[MURDOCK]: You think the fielders today with their huge gloves, they catch things they wouldn't have caught in the old days?
[MURDOCK]: Because the gloves are so big.
[BARNHART]: Oh, they might.
[BARNHART]: An awful lot of outfielders only use one hand to catch them all now.
[MURDOCK]: The glove's so big, you can't miss.
[WOMAN 2]: He never used to fall down and roll over and do things like that.
[WOMAN 2]: I don't ever remember seeing them do that when I was at any of the games.
[WOMAN 2]: And I used to go to every one when I was out there.
[MURDOCK]: What was your biggest thrill in seeing him play?
[MURDOCK]: Does anything stand out?
[WOMAN 2]: Oh, I don't know.
[WOMAN 2]: I just sat with my mouth shut.
[WOMAN 2]: I just always liked to see him do.
[WOMAN 2]: If he did all right and if he didn't do all right.
[MURDOCK]: Did the wives sit together?
[WOMAN 2]: I started it, but I sat downstairs.
[WOMAN 2]: I sat up in the box.
[WOMAN 1]: You and Mrs. Kovalevski, she said she never wanted to sit near any of the other players' wives.
[WOMAN 1]: She'd go off and sit in the stand by herself.
[SPEAKER 01]: There was a lot of the wives.
[BARNHART]: get in arguments about their husbands' best play or something.
[WOMAN 2]: I never opened my mouth.
[WOMAN 2]: I went to watch the games when I was born.
[MURDOCK]: Did you enjoy the games?
[WOMAN 2]: Oh, yes.
[WOMAN 2]: You believe I did.
[WOMAN 2]: I went to both World Series.
[MURDOCK]: How'd you two happen to meet?
[WOMAN 2]: Oh, we lived about a mile within each other.
[WOMAN 2]: We lived in Buck Valley, Pennsylvania.
[MURDOCK]: So you knew each other from, really, the early days?
[WOMAN 2]: We didn't go to the same country school, but they had different country schools.
[WOMAN 2]: You didn't live too far apart, what was it, down the line?
[MURDOCK]: Did you ever play in a no-hit game?
[BARNHART]: No.
[MURDOCK]: Did any pirates, pitchers, pitch any no-hitters?
[WOMAN 2]: We never talked baseball after he left the park, after a bit.
[MURDOCK]: Even after a good day?
[WOMAN 2]: Even after a good day.
[WOMAN 2]: The only thing I remember about him was
[WOMAN 2]: If we went anyplace, you know, he always went to the ballpark before I did.
[WOMAN 2]: And every hairpin he saw, he picked up.
[WOMAN 2]: That was a two-base hit for me.
[WOMAN 1]: Oh, really?
[WOMAN 2]: And that was his superstition.
[WOMAN 2]: And it worked pretty good, too.
[BARNHART]: Isn't that something?
[MURDOCK]: So baseball players are superstitious, huh?
[BARNHART]: Well, we're all superstitious.
[MURDOCK]: Don't step on the foul line or anything.
[MURDOCK]: Not at all?
[MURDOCK]: You never talked baseball?
[WOMAN 2]: No.
[WOMAN 2]: Not after he got home, no.
[WOMAN 1]: Well, he had finished his day's work and that was that.
[MURDOCK]: Well, I mean, he'd gotten three doubles or something.
[MURDOCK]: You didn't talk about it?
[WOMAN 2]: No, I didn't say it was a good day, because he had a good many good days.
[WOMAN 2]: I know it, and he knows it, so I thought about it.
[WOMAN 2]: One of his clippings, I remember it.
[WOMAN 2]: They said, when he came in from right field, he neither looked right nor left.
[WOMAN 2]: The grandstands, anybody, he just walked right straight ahead.
[WOMAN 2]: I always called him old eagle-eye.
[MURDOCK]: It sounds like you didn't get very nervous or excited during the games from what I gather here, is that true?
[WOMAN 2]: I don't know.
[WOMAN 1]: You and me both.
[WOMAN 2]: I think I need to have a look at it.
[WOMAN 1]: I don't see how...
[WOMAN 1]: I think if I were a wife,
[WOMAN 1]: and my husband was playing.
[BARNHART]: Well, I'd have to go off in a corner by myself and watch the game.
[WOMAN 2]: No, I didn't mind a bit.
[WOMAN 1]: Really?
[WOMAN 1]: Oh, I would be a nervous wreck.
[MURDOCK]: Did you ever see him get hit, for example?
[WOMAN 2]: No, I didn't see him get hit that day.
[WOMAN 2]: He broke his elbow.
[WOMAN 2]: Oh, man.
[MURDOCK]: That was by a pitched ball?
[WOMAN 2]: I guess it was.
[WOMAN 2]: He was home for a little while.
[WOMAN 2]: Where did you go?
[WOMAN 2]: Where did they send you to get your arm set?
[MURDOCK]: Home setter reached?
[BARNHART]: Yeah.
[WOMAN 2]: Was it home setter Reese?
[WOMAN 2]: Or was it Youngstown?
[MURDOCK]: He was in Youngstown.
[BARNHART]: I don't remember what the...
[WOMAN 2]: But he came home for a while.
[BARNHART]: So lost for a while, too.
[BARNHART]: There wasn't much setting to do.
[BARNHART]: I believe so.
[MURDOCK]: It was your throwing arm, huh?
[MURDOCK]: Did you have any trouble?
[BARNHART]: With my broken arm.
[MURDOCK]: When was that, in 1922?
[MURDOCK]: Maybe 26, huh?
[MURDOCK]: That was a good year.
[MURDOCK]: He played 76 games.
[MURDOCK]: Did you have trouble throwing after that?
[MURDOCK]: Did you come back?
[BARNHART]: It took a while.
[WOMAN 2]: And we had a Christmas card from Tom Shane two years ago, and he wrote on it that we've been playing, you know, now we've been millionaires.
[WOMAN 1]: That's right.
[MURDOCK]: Some of them are pretty bitter about that.
[MURDOCK]: I mean, how do you feel about these modern players and their salaries as against their abilities?
[MURDOCK]: I mean, $4.3 million contracts.
[WOMAN 2]: A lot of them did a lot of good, though, for, you know, other charities and things.
[BARNHART]: Tom sent me a Christmas card every year at Pittsburgh.
[WOMAN 2]: Two years ago?
[BARNHART]: Just two years ago.
[BARNHART]: I don't know whether he died or... Well, we'll have to find out.
[WOMAN 2]: Mr. Murdoch said he never heard that he died, so he must still be living.
[MURDOCK]: Yeah, I think he is.
[WOMAN 2]: He could be sick or something, you know.
[BARNHART]: He lived in California.
[MURDOCK]: Did he play with the pirates then?
[BARNHART]: Pardon?
[MURDOCK]: Did he play with the Pirates when you were there?
[BARNHART]: Yeah.
[BARNHART]: We got to come back and correct the job.
[WOMAN 1]: And he said at one time they were all broken.
[MURDOCK]: Do you have any pictures of yourself?
[MURDOCK]: Scrapbooks or clippings of your playing days?
[BARNHART]: Oh, I have a scrapbook.
[BARNHART]: A scrapbook about that big.
[MURDOCK]: Is that right?
[WOMAN 2]: That's where they had him that time.
[MURDOCK]: Suppose I could take a look at it.
[WOMAN 2]: All night and all day and all morning.
[WOMAN 1]: Oh, really?
[WOMAN 2]: Yeah, it did.
[WOMAN 2]: One was from New York, I think, yesterday.
[WOMAN 2]: And it was a long envelope.
[WOMAN 2]: And you know what it had in it?
[WOMAN 2]: Just a postcard.
[WOMAN 2]: A pen and paper email.
[WOMAN 2]: I mean, they're 10 cents.
[WOMAN 2]: I hadn't bought any, and I said, well, I looked at it.
[WOMAN 2]: I wanted to know how much it was, and it was 10 cents.
[WOMAN 2]: And this last three autographs.
[WOMAN 2]: And then some of Bonnie's picture, and one time,
[WOMAN 2]: They sent a good picture of him, and I'm sorry I didn't...